If you go anywhere on Instagram,
people talk about good hooks, good setups,
good
payoffs, how to go viral.
They talk about all these things,
but they never actually
show you or explain the nuance behind it.
My name's James Smith.
I work with hundreds of businesses every
single year to help them make more money
online using social media.
So there's a link in the description.
You go into there, you put in your name,
your Instagram, I add you to the list,
pick you at random.
Don't do any prep work beforehand.
Let's begin.
Oh, Black Rock Kitchen Design,
150 followers.
You should be doing these videos, brother.
Design, supply,
and installation of beautiful German
kitchens. Wow, okay.
This is interesting. I like this.
Founder led. The guy's front and center.
We've got good thumbnails, so if you
were perusing through the page,
you could be
like, "Oh, actually,
I do want to have a look at that." Let's
have a quick look
here. Clean, luxury German kitchens. Okay.
Call for an appointment. Showroom visit.
Oh, this looks decent.
I love this stuff because every person
that owns a home is kind of always
thinking,
"How can I make my kitchen better?" The
kitchen is probably the most underrated
room in the house. Okay,
let's listen to your content.
So today we post the following video about
three things you should never do in your
kitchen. Got a whole lot of hate,
but it also got 5.4 million views and
over 100,000 likes. Number one,
never put your sink on the island.
Sinks are the messiest part of the
kitchen.
Why would you want to create a beautiful
kitchen and then spend your days staring
at the washing up?
Keep your island either completely clear
or just have the hob on
it.
That's an interesting one.
Controversial take. I don't know.
It's just got nothing to do with the
content.
I'm just thinking,
sometimes you're washing a glass,
giving someone a glass of
water. I don't know. And also,
who does their washing up in the sink?
If we can afford your bathrooms,
we've got a dishwasher.
Put your sink on a wall then,
so you can keep your island clear of
clutter and
those nasty dirty dishes. Number two
So I feel like these points are fantastic.
I do like the introduction because you're
kind of piggybacking off the video that
went viral.
But each one of this could probably be its
own video.
So for instance, you go,
"Last week we were at 5.1 million views
because I
said there should not be a sink on the
island.
Let me give you four reasons why you
should absolutely not do this
if you design
your own kitchen." Then
that should be a standalone reel.
Then this one
Save money by having cupboards instead of
drawers. This is such a false economy.
Yes, cupboards are cheaper than drawers,
but they're also much less efficient, so
you end up needing more of them.
So this is another video altogether,
and I'm not telling you how to do content.
You're crushing it. But this one,
I would say shelves waste more space than
anything in the kitchen.
And although they
are cheaper than getting cupboards, with
cupboards,
we can access things at the back.
And you go, "If you don't believe me,
open the nearest cupboard to you right
now.
Now look at the back of a shelf."
And you go, "There's stuff in there
that went off
in Second World War.
There's stuff back there
that your mum bought from that Happy
Shopper back in '93."
And you can have a bit of fun with it
because I think this is
another fantastic point.
With drawers, you can instantly see
and access everything.
With cupboards,
stuff gets buried at the back,
never to be seen again.
Saving money on your kitchen is fine,
but just do it in the right way.
Don't compromise on the fundamentals of a
good hardworking kitchen.
Number three, have tiles for splashbacks.
Tiles are just not a good choice for your
splashbacks.
They look too busy
and the grout discolors over time.
Nowadays there are much better options.
Glass to stone to laminated panels.
Okay, I love this. For me,
if you want to do five points like this in
good
detail, it's a YouTube video.
Each one of these, I believe,
should be its own.
I didn't know what a splashback was.
So this thing right here
is called a splashback.
It's a hard-
Read my mind, brother
...
wearing panel installed on the walls above
your kitchen worktops.
Its main function is to give you an easy
to clean-
I would say you're doing very well
already, but I'd say play the
game with the hooks.
Everyone neglects this part of their
kitchen. This is called a splashback.
And everyone's like, "Oh,
do you know what? I never even knew.
Maybe I'm neglecting mine."
There's a really neat little bench seat
area with coat hooks here.
We've got a couple of drawers underneath.
Perfect for some cleaning supplies,
what have you.
Then our coat hooks here,
and then our nice tongue
and groove paneling on the
back.
Again, I still feel like a hook
or some form of setup.
You could be like,
"Your front door needs to have one of
these areas, and I'm going
to explain why." Because people really
want to understand what they're getting
into very early on in content.
Here's everything you need to know about
kitchen islands.
Perfect.
For one,
we recommend one meter between the island
and the nearest wall or run of
units.
You can squeeze this to 90 centimeters-
So then I would say maybe be playing
something like, "Don't make these mistakes
when you design your kitchen.
Don't make these mistakes
when creating a kitchen
island." There's almost like if I
was to say how to make 100 pounds more
next
year, people are like, "Okay." But
if I made a video on how to save yourself
an
unnecessary spending of 100 pounds,
they're much more inclined to listen.
So anything that incurs a loss plays into
loss aversion and basically people
find the psychological pain of loss
is twice as bad as the equivalent gain.
I'll explain. Let's say you go outside,
you find a tenner on the floor.
You're like, "Oh sick,
found a tenner."
That would make you like a five out of 10
happy. But if you lost a tenner,
you'd be like, "For fuck's sake,
I'm fucking
an idiot.
I can't believe I lost a tenner." And
that would make you a minus 10
unhappy.
So really because it's 10 pounds either
way you would expect the
equivalent gain and loss to be on similar
playing fields but it's not how the mind
works.
So rather than telling people how to do
things in their kitchen, by telling
them what not to do and the pitfalls
and mistakes to
avoid could potentially tap into their
psychology even better.
So for instance rather than me saying this
is how to do your meal prep, don't make
these mistakes doing your meal prep.
People are like,
"What mistake?" It just tunes them in a
bit more.
[upbeat music]
Whatever!
See I feel like maybe the music's cool
but I'd rather you just spoke to me and
said,
"Have you ever seen anything open like
this in a kitchen?
This is called a..."
I'm loving this by the way.
I could just do this whole video on your
page.
I think the hardest thing for people
when they're buying a new kitchen is that
they're buying the kitchen from a
salesman, not a designer most of the
time.
Maybe potentially a question here.
Who's best to sell you a kitchen?
A designer or a salesperson?
And that's not their fault.
It's just the sad realities of-
Mr. Incredible Hairline. Mr. Quiff.
Now this is you as you are. Love that.
Let's say we're at a zero and 10
is you as a TV presenter.
"Hey guys, welcome to the show.
Great to see you.
Today we've got a..."
And then minus 10 would be you like,
"Hello
everyone," like Stephen Hawkins.
Can we try a plus four?
Because you are presenting in some way.
Even I would permit you putting the mic in
your hand so you'd be like, "Come with
me, take a look at this kitchen.
We're going to look at some things to
avoid but
some of the things
that this kitchen has done so well."
Rather than the hands in
the pocket.
We got a bit of a defensive posture.
I feel like you don't know what to do with
your hands.
It's like seeing
that at Thundercats nights.
"Don't know what to do with my hands."
So this thing right here
is called a waterfall end panel.
It's where you take your worktop material
down the side of the cabinet to the
floor. It gives you a beautiful,
hard-wearing...
So this kitchen's a really good example of
our favorite way of designing a
kitchen. So we keep our--
So we've got a really beautiful-
So this is great.
I'm going to throw something out there
that I want you to do as
homework. And it could bomb,
but it could do well.
I want us to play with some carousel
posts, and each carousel post
is going to pose
a question.
How much does this kitchen island cost?
Then as you swipe through,
you're going to show me different
components.
Marble, 1,500 pounds. Woodwork,
800 pounds.
Labor, 3K. Plug sockets, optional extra,
250 pounds.
So then you can say,
this kitchen island cost you seven grand.
I'm just throwing it out there.
Going to tell you a story as to why.
Outdoor my house... I can't talk today.
Built a shower, love it.
Neighbor saw me in the shower. I said,
"Oi,
next time you come back from the beach,
get in it." They said,
"How much does it cost?" I said,
"I don't know, but I can
give you the guy's number," because he
hadn't charged me yet.
They said, "No, no, no,
we're not bothered." And then
when I found out how much the
shower cost me, I went and I told them.
They went, "Oh,
we'll get his number." The thing wasn't
did they want the shower.
The thing,
the deciding factor for them
was how much it is.
And when they had the information on how
much it is, they went, "Okay, actually,
that's reasonable within our budget.
We're now going to pursue action." So I
think I would love to see you bring the
price into frame, because guess what?
If it's like 10 grand,
eight out of 10 people are going to go,
"How much?
How much do you spend on a kitchen?
You can't spend 10K on a
kitchen." But then two out of 10 people
are going to go, "Hmm, 30?
Should we get the kitchen done?" Do you
know what I mean?
And then to those eight out of 10 people,
if they can't afford it, just let them be
window shoppers.
We all love drawers.
Here's three things you need to know about
the most important
drawer of them all, your cutlery drawer.
Number one,
the best place for your cutlery drawer is-
See, everything you said before that
is a waste.
This visual here,
if your cutlery drawer is opposite your
dishwasher, you're losing hours.
You're losing days a year.
If there's one thing you want to plan in
your house, it's that.
I've never thought of this before in my
life. Where's ours?
Ours is next to it as well, actually.
Never thought about that.
That is a million view reel.
We all love drawers.
This bit I think is redundant.
You should be there with the drawer next
to the dishwasher going,
"When you design your kitchen,
it's imperative that these
two are next to each other.
Why?" Do you know what I mean?
Because so many people
are going to scroll away
when they see a tall
guy with an impeccable hairline with a
quiff because they don't know you yet.
So unless they're one of the 150,000
people that follow you,
they're just going to
leave. But-
We all love drawers.
Here's three things you need to know about
the most important
drawer of them all, your cutlery drawer.
But when I arrive on this bit here,
I'm like, "This is fire." Fire
visual. So yeah.
[upbeat music]
These five things get used...
So this thing right here is-
And again,
I'd just love to see some stuff where you
go through people's
kitchens that you fitted, and you just go,
"This is why we did this.
This is why we did this." Also,
if the homeowners wouldn't mind getting
involved, mic them up and be like, "Steve,
why have you gone with this?" Bring
other people into it.
But I absolutely love this.
You're absolutely crushing it.
There, you've already got a perfect meal.
I'm just saying, let's add a bit of salt.
Let's add a little bit of salt.
But killing it, bro.
720 posts, 150,000 followers, smashing it.
Love it.
What a star that is. Okay, Shai Arreola.
94kg classic street lifting champ. What
is street lifting?
Okay,
this looks to me like just a load of your
workouts. So when I get here,
I don't know what you do.
[upbeat music] I'm done. So in essence,
this to me just looks
like a page where you just lift weights.
Don't know how you are to help me.
There's no call to actions.
This content, remember,
is supposed to be about me.
It's supposed to be about helping me to do
the things that you can do and you can
help me with. Next. Andy Thrive.
"I help men go
from stuck to thriving all year round
through structured training,
simple nutrition, and good accountability.
DM me Thrive to get started." All right,
if Thrive's your surname, that's okay.
If not, I'm just not mad on the word,
to be perfectly honest.
None of my boys ever say like,
"I'm thriving at the moment.
I am thriving." How many DMs for Thrive do
you get?
I'm going to do it now as well.
What's the point? What's the point?
DM me Thrive.
There's not even a chatbot set up here,
bruv.
You could've been like,
"Thank you so much for that.
So glad you found my page.
I'm going to get back to you as soon as
possible.
In the meantime,
here's a fat loss lead magnet for you to
get started." What's the
point? DM me Thrive.
It doesn't do anything.
I just sit here with my dick in my hand
fucking like, "What am I going to do?" And
what is this,
an Instagram link to another page that's
got more followers?
How has your Thrive online coaching got
more followers? That makes no sense.
My story.
You need to stop being in a calorie
deficit all the time.
Seriously,
if you feel like you're always dieting
and it's not working, this is
why. If you're someone who's con-
Don't like these transitions
...
constantly trying to eat in a deficit but-
Wait, there's three hooks here.
Let's go into this again
You need to stop being in a calorie
deficit-
Statement hook
... all the time. Seriously,
if you feel like you're always dieting
and it's not
working, this is why.
Another hook.
If you're someone who's constantly trying
to eat in a deficit but never lose
weight,
or you say things like calorie deficits
don't work, you're doing it wrong.
Third hook.
You see, a calo-
Terrible transition
... deficit is a phase.
It's just one part of the process until
you reach your
goal. It's not a lifestyle.
It's not supposed to last forever.
You see,
when you work with the right coach,
they'll teach you how to come out of
that deficit properly.
They'll bring you to maintenance,
so you can eat more food,
you can enjoy your life,
and still keep the weight off
that you've lost.
Fat loss isn't about so-
Sorry, it's just a bit boring,
and that's me being constructive and kind.
I don't like the transitions.
I don't like this kind of candid camera
angle in the
car. It's all very jarring.
This is Suzanne. She's o-
Cheap mic way too close to your mouth
... always been into fitness.
Training wasn't new to her, but she knew-
Okay, going to throw this out there.
No one cares about your clients.
This is the nicest thing I can say to you.
No one gives a fuck about your clients.
They only care about themselves
... she had more in her.
I felt like I could-
No one cares. No one cares. Now,
if Suzanne has accomplished a result,
let's say
she lost four kilograms,
make a video about how your audience can
lose four
kilograms, then tie it back.
If you don't believe me, this is Suzanne.
Suzanne is your reason to believe.
She's not what the video
is about because ultimately,
I couldn't give a fuck about
Suzanne. But if you go,
"If you want to lose four kilograms in two
weeks, this is
what I did with Suzanne,
and a lot of people said it wouldn't work,
and it did.
Let me explain." You know what I mean?
Last year, we lost our gym
and rebuilt our lives,
and I want to share some lessons
I've learned from that.
Again, sorry to say, don't care.
This is me a whole year into my
relationship.
Again, don't care.
Are you not seeing results?
The plebiest thing a personal trainer can
say.
You're about to see loads of before
and after photos as we-
Who's that? What's this? Last year,
we lost our gym. Don't care.
So this is me-
Don't ever start a video with so ...
at 19. Don't worry, I know.
So I'd already been training-
Don't care ...
if you think you don't have time for-
Get a proper mic, bro, because that is
horrible. That
literally sounds worse than just the
iPhone ... Ayan, this is for you.
See, you don't have a time problem.
You know what?
I'm going to give you an example here.
So when people talk really close to the
microphone, it doesn't sound that good.
You have a priority problem. This
is Kevin. Don't care.
So what we need to do,
we really need to think about client
problems,
problems your clients are facing,
then solve them in the content because I
just
watched about 10 of your reels,
and none of them spoke to me.
I could do with being leaner.
I could do with feeling better.
I could do with eating better.
And you gave me no help. Nothing.
Talking about your gym,
talking about your stuff, yappa, yappa,
yappa.
There's no helping me, brother. Come on.
"I want to get on a video,
and I want to be unable to leave." "Did
you know that
this exercise builds the rear delts to
30..." Come on.
I would love to build my rear delts.
What is it?
I've got a hard stop in seven minutes.
Got to get my hair cut.
The Alignment Coach. All right.
I'm going to throw it out there,
do not know
what alignment means.
I didn't nearly lose my life because I
was unlook-
You don't need motivation,
you need standards. Hmm.
I was so stupid. I kept thinking
that I needed more-
I'm going to imagine I'm a cold audience
here because about a billion people on
Instagram don't follow you,
so we need to pretend that someone's cold.
Fair play.
Well done, sir.
But you can find inspiration from any
source if you look-
See,
I'm not really getting spoken to on any of
these
... I was caught up in a life of crime,
selling drugs, addic- There
was a period in
my life where-
Was there a-
You don't self-destruct when life's hard.
I do it and you do it.
In fact, the pan feel dead in-
So I need you to start talking to your
target audience and
demographic, and I watched about 10 there,
and I have no idea who that is.
Founder of the Alignment Protocol.
I just feel like this
is such a terrible use of real estate,
really.
You could've told me what you were.
Instead,
you told me you're the founder of
something you made up.
Aligning body, being,
and business for men ready to operate at a
higher
standard.
I still don't really know what that means.
I'd love you to just say, even
if you say something generic like,
"I help men take
control of their lives." Something like
that.
And I don't really know what alignment
means, and I'm a coach that coaches
coaches, so I should know what that means,
really.
Okay, let's go for one more.
Vanisha Footwear Cleaning and
Restoration Services. Hmm. One second,
guys.
[air whooshing] What are you saying, bro?
Back to pre mate.
Got some likes on that. Crease taken out.
Yeah.
Some repainting actually needed. Okay.
To be fresh, bro.
I know you can work your magic. Cheers,
bro. No worries, mate.
Oh, okay.
I'm hooked. I'll tell you right now,
for any of you that don't know, we are
watching a story unfold. This is a story.
It's a story about a man who comes to a
shop with shoddy trainers.
It's a story about a man who brings his
Creps back to life, and
we're watching.
[brushing] ASMR.
Oh.
[spraying]
I like the eco vibe to this. Like,
"Don't buy new trainers.
Your old ones are fine." I need to hear
that.
I've binned off whites because they've got
a stain on them.
This is great, by the way.
[upbeat music]
This is kind of cool.
I wouldn't mind some kind of founder-led
voice on this.
So here today,
we've got a pair of these Gucci Creps.
This part of the trainer's often the bit
that wears out.
Most people would throw these away at this
point, but- Oh, they're Chanel.
I thought they were Gucci. Oh, yeah ...
and being like, "Oh, watch this.
Today we're going to get this shoe back to
brand new," saving this person.
And you could even be like,
"This shoe's 700 pound.
We're saving them the money." I wouldn't
mind to hear your voice in here.
Oh my God. This is actually insane. Ooh!
[spraying] Okay. Maybe in your hooks,
I'd love
for you to show me the before, the after,
the before, the after, then get
into the story.
That would be a bit of a preview hook so
we could see what is about
to happen. That would make me very,
very happy. But this is great, mate.
This is great. This is really good.
I'm loving this.
I would also love to see some YouTube
content like, "How I Made
100K Last Year Cleaning Trainers."
Because you could just get some views on
that.
I watched a video the other day about a
company that sells ice cubes and makes $2
million a year.
So there's got to be legs in that.
All right.
Short one today because I've got to get my
hair cut because I'm going bald.
You put your Instagrams in the link below,
and I'll get round to it later on this
week. It's been great.
If you're ready to watch another one of
these, check out
this video here.
I'll send you to the last one. All right.
Bye-bye.